[{"question":"A resistor of 3 kΩ, a 0.05 μF capacitor, and a 120 mH coil are in series across a 5 kHz, 20 V ac source. What is the impedance, expressed in polar form?","answers":{"a":"636 Ω ","b":"3,769 Ω","c":"433 Ω","d":"4,337 Ω"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"A 10 Ω resistor, a 90 mH coil, and a 0.015 μF capacitor are in series across an ac source. The impedance magnitude at 1,200 Hz below fr is ?","answers":{"a":"1,616 Ω","b":"161 Ω","c":"3,387 Ω","d":"1,771 Ω"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"In a certain series resonant circuit, VC = 125 V, VL = 125 V, and VR = 40 V. The value of the source voltage is ?","answers":{"a":"125 V","b":"250 V","c":"290 V","d":"40 V"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"A resonant circuit has a lower critical frequency of 7 kHz and an upper critical frequency of 13 kHz. The bandwidth of the circuit is ?","answers":{"a":"7 kHz","b":"13 kHz","c":"20 kHz","d":"6 kHz"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"A 200 Ω resistor, a coil with 30 Ω of reactance, and a capacitor of unknown reactance are in series across an ac source. The circuit is at resonance. Circuit impedance is ?","answers":{"a":"230 Ω","b":"170 Ω","c":"200 Ω","d":"Cannot be determined"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"At series resonance, the inductive reactance and capacitive reactance are never equal.","answers":{"a":"True","b":"false"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"The ratio of Inductive reactance and capacitive reactance in an AC circuit is ?","answers":{"a":"1","b":"WC<sup>2</sup>","c":"W<sup>2</sup>L","d":"W<sup>2</sup>LC"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"Calculate the quality factor Q for an RLC circuit having R= 10Ω , C= 30μF and L = 27mh.","answers":{"a":"3","b":"6","c":"9","d":"15"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"In an AC circuit R= 0ohm, XL= 8ohm and Xc= 6ohm phase difference between voltage and current is ?","answers":{"a":"110<sup>0</sup>","b":"90<sup>0 </sup>","c":"37<sup>0 </sup>","d":"12<sup>0 </sup>"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"When the frequency applied to a series RLC circuit is increased, the current of the circuit is ?","answers":{"a":"Increases","b":"First decreases and then increases after reaching a minimum value","c":"First increases then decreases after reaching a maximum value","d":"Decreases"},"correctAnswer":"c"}]
